<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>2017s on Whippo Lab</title>
    <link>/2017/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 2017s on Whippo Lab</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2017 Ross Whippo</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/2017/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Benthic Photo Processing for CoralNet</title>
      <link>/2017/12/05/benthic-photo-processing-for-coralnet/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/12/05/benthic-photo-processing-for-coralnet/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This week I got back to processing the benthic photoquadrats from the 2017 MarineGEO Carrie Bow Cay field campaign. I reviewed the 2015 photos which we uploaded to &lt;a href=&#34;https://coralnet.ucsd.edu/&#34;&gt;CoralNet&lt;/a&gt; and saw that some of the photos were not color-corrected. I also double checked the cropping of the photos and found that most photos were cropped to a 54cm x 82cm estimated area covered, though some photos appear to be larger that that. I will need to investigate this further.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To process the 2017 photos from Carrie Bow Reef, House Reef, Carrie Bow Patch Reef, Curlew Patch Reef, South Reef, and Tobacco Reef I decided to standardize color correction using GIMP 2.8.18 following a protocol modified from the Script Fu provided below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;r&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;; med.scm version 2.4v2
; 12 November 2007
; A Script-Fu script to compensate for underwater colour loss
; at greater than 5m
; Modified to replace deprecated procedures, to work with GIMP 2.4

; This program is free software; you can redistribute it and/or modify
; it under the terms of the GNU General Public License as published by
; the Free Software Foundation; either version 2 of the License, or
; (at your option) any later version.
;
; This program is distributed in the hope that it will be useful,
; but WITHOUT ANY WARRANTY; without even the implied warranty of
; MERCHANTABILITY or FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE.  See the
; GNU General Public License for more details.

; You should have received a copy of the GNU General Public License
; along with this program; if not, write to the Free Software
; Foundation, Inc., 675 Mass Ave, Cambridge, MA 02139, USA.

; Only tested on v2.4

(define (script-fu-med img photo)

    (gimp-image-undo-group-start img)

    ;first copy of photo, set foreground to grey, fill with grey and set mode to color
    (define uw-layer (car (gimp-layer-copy photo 1)))
    (gimp-image-add-layer img uw-layer -1)
    (gimp-drawable-set-name uw-layer &amp;quot;red enhance 2&amp;quot;)
    (gimp-context-set-foreground &amp;#39;(128 128 128))
    (gimp-edit-fill uw-layer 0)
    (gimp-layer-set-mode uw-layer COLOR-MODE)

    ;second copy of photo, set background to red, fill with red and set mode to multiply
    (define uw1-layer (car (gimp-layer-copy photo 1)))
    (gimp-image-add-layer img uw1-layer -1)
    (gimp-drawable-set-name uw1-layer &amp;quot;red enhance 2a&amp;quot;)
    (gimp-context-set-background &amp;#39;(255 0 0))
    (gimp-edit-fill uw1-layer 1)
    (gimp-layer-set-mode uw1-layer MULTIPLY-MODE)

    ;merge down red to grey (clip-to-image) change mode to screen
    (define uw-layer (car (gimp-image-merge-down img uw1-layer 1)))
    (gimp-layer-set-mode uw-layer SCREEN-MODE)

    ;set opacity to 50%, tweak up for deep (very green images) or down for shallow
    (gimp-layer-set-opacity uw-layer 50)

    ;clean
    (gimp-image-undo-group-end img)
    (gimp-displays-flush)
)


(script-fu-register &amp;quot;script-fu-med&amp;quot;
        _&amp;quot;&amp;lt;Image&amp;gt;/Script-F_u/_Underwater Photos/Red Enhance _2&amp;quot;
        &amp;quot;Based on the mandrake method for Photoshop. Translated to GIMP by meddler. See www.scubaboard.com for the original articles.&amp;quot;
        &amp;quot;www.tankedup-imaging.com&amp;quot;
        &amp;quot;Tanked Up Underwater Imaging&amp;quot;
        &amp;quot;12 November 2007&amp;quot;
        &amp;quot;&amp;quot;
        SF-IMAGE &amp;quot;Image&amp;quot; 0
        SF-DRAWABLE &amp;quot;Drawable&amp;quot; 0
)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
